

What I Do_

- Develop efficient solutions to modern data problems
- Create intuitive, interactive graphics that tell your data's story
- Translate analytic findings into actionable business insights

Career Interests

- Natural Language Processing
- Data Stream/IOT Analytics
- Medical/Healthcare Applications
- Business Analytics

Core Skills

Primary Languages: R, Python, SQL

Other Languages: JavaScript, Go, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: Shiny, ggplot, Flask, Tensorflow, Keras, Caret

Competencies: Data Mining and Cleaning, Data Visualization, Dashboard Development, Business Analytics, Forecasting, Natural Language Processing, Statistics, Experimental Design, Machine Learning. Artificial Intelligence

Education

2014-2015: M.S. Biomedical Science - Colorado State University

· Advanced coursework in human physiology with a concentration in Neuroscience

2010-2014: B.S Biomedical Science - Colorado State University

- Foundational knowledge across the medical sciences
- Quantitative coursework in Biostatistics and Calculus

Career Summary

2017 - Present: Medical Research Scientist III

MedAware Systems Inc.

Performed a variety of data-centric roles overseeing the acquisition, maintenance, and integrity of data in the world's largest Alzheimer's database.

Key Responsibilities

- Ensured the integrity and completeness of data acquisition
- Developed data validation tools and algorithms
- Programmed algorithms for the extraction and aliasing of data from text
- Created and pursued novel research topics for publication
- Produced high quality data visualizations
- Assisted in the design and implementation of UI/UX improvements

2016 - 2017: Medical Research Scientist I

MedAware Systems Inc.

Flourished in a fast paced start-up environment while involved in clinical trial data acquisition.

Key Responsibilities

- Facilitated meta-analysis via data acquisition
- Improved data intake through the standardization of novel data concepts
- Performed quality assurance on new web features

2014: Microbiology Teaching Assistant Colorado State University

Organized lectures and study groups for an upper level, general Microbiology course. Lectured to groups of up to 100 students and provided interactive, small group tutoring for difficult concepts.

Key Repsonsibilities

- Organized and lectured for large groups
- Small group tutoring to help struggling students succeed
- Crafted interdisciplinary exam questions to test students' ability to integrate concepts

2012: Undergraduate Research Assistant

Colorado State University

Investigated histone biochemistry and the effects of protein truncation on binding kinetics.

Key Responsibilities

- ELISA
- Protein Purification
- Fluorescence Resonance Energy Transfer (FRET) Assays